《紅 : アスマ…》
(シカマル)アスマーッ！
アスマ…。
Aren't you being a little too laid back?
(飛段)こっちは終わったぜ。
Oh, well you know, things were
pretty tense around here recently
(角都)こっちもすぐ終わらせる。
with the incident in the Sand Village.
(コテツ)ちくしょう…。
But now that it's been settled...
I'm suddenly overcome
with exhaustion...
Even so, we don't know
what's going to happen next.
このヤロウ…。
Only by being cautious at all times
are we able to prevent...
You won't last if
you remain cautious at all times.
このヤロウが！
Come on, relax, relax!
ケッ…。
It's not good to tease weak ones.
I set the alarm clock
before I went to bed last night,
and here, I get up before
the alarm goes off.
《ちくしょう…
オレはなんて無力なんだ…》
I can't bring myself to turn off
the alarm.
《シカマル : 羽根？》
But if I don't,
then the annoying ring won't stop.
あ!? なんだ こりゃ！
It's such a pain just thinking
about this whole thing!
カラスなんかで オレらを
やれると思ってんのか!?
なめんなよ！
Seconds!
What is that?
(角都)目くらましか…。
黒刀！
(いの)シカマル。
Move, move, move!
(いの)助けにきたわよ。
いの…。
Last spurt! Goal!
(イズモ)シカマルを安全な場所に。
はい！
First place!
(アオバ)油断するな チョウジ。
(チョウジ)うん！
Sadly, second place!
- What kind of race is that?
- Beats me...
チッ！
Hey Lee, you need to train more.
《飛段 : 増援か…》
Yes! I will try to be first place next time.
But, there is regrettable news.
Wh-What is it?
Lee, you are not second place.
(ライドウ)大丈夫か？
あぁ…。
それより アスマ隊長を…。
You are...third place!
(チョウジ)アスマ先生！
Huh?!
Second place is Kakashi,
whom I am carrying!
Kakashi, you are too lucky!
You don't need to thank me.
I feel like I learned another
important lesson from you.
As usual, I can't keep up
with their craziness.
まだ かすかに脈がある！
チョウジ！ すぐに アスマ先生を
木ノ葉病院へ！
Although we did run along after them.
いの お前は同行して 医療忍術で
少しでも回復させるんだ！
Ridiculous!
Okay, everyone's here, eh?!
急げ！
わかった！
うん！
Then let's go report to
Lady Tsunade right away.
Um, Guy Sensei...
賞金首は渡さん。
What is it?
Kakashi Sensei is...
クソ！
Huh? Oh!
Guess it's the hospital before reporting.
(アオバ)オレたちが食い止める。
その隙に アスマさんを運べ！
The New Target
(飛段)どんだけ ジタバタしようと
お前らは 神に捧げられる贄だ。
だから… ん？
もう少し 待ってくんねえかな。
これからが いいとこなんだ ホント。
Oh! He's awake!
So I'm back here again...
Good job, Kakashi.
Master...
Lady Tsunade...
No, Kakashi Sensei!
Don't push yourself.
I examined you earlier,
but you need to be in bed for a week.
(ペイン)二尾を封印する。
今すぐ 跳べ。 最優先だ。
It will take a few more days
until you can return to duty.
I guess that's how it goes...
Seems it will still take a while until
you can master the new Sharingan.
だから 言ってんだろ。
もう少しだけだってよぉ！
Yes...
Just rest. Try not to push yourself
for a while.
(角都)飛段 やめろ。
《アオバ : 誰かと 通信してるのか？》
Team Guy should rest today too.
You can turn in the report later.
チッ！
また すぐに戻る。
Yes!
Let's go, Shizune.
覚悟はしておけ。
Yes.
Oh...Master!
(ペイン)フッ 世話の焼けるヤツらだ。
Is it regarding that matter?
Yes.
Did you tell Kakashi?
Since Kakashi Sensei has been
like that all this time, I haven't yet...
How about Naruto?
I thought I should first consult you...
行くぞ 飛段。
あの クソリーダー。
今度呪ってやろうか ったくよぉ！
Give me the details.
《どういうことだ？
一旦 退く気か？》
It's what I heard from
the Akatsuki member, Sasori.
先生！
アスマ先生！
He said it was a reward for beating him...
いの！ チョウジ！
急いで アスマを連れていくぞ 早く！
In ten days,
go to the Tenchi Bridge
だから テメエら➡
located in the Village Hidden
in the Grass at high noon.
オレらが戻ってくるまで
じっとしてろ！
I've got a spy working as one of
Orochimaru's subordinates...
ソイツは もう死ぬからよ！
くぅ…。
I was supposed to rendezvous...
with him...there...
じゃあな！ クソヤロウども！
In ten days...at Tenchi Bridge, huh...
(シカマル)チョウジ いの 早くしろ！
Four days has passed,
so it will be in six days.
(いの)私は 医療忍術を！
(チョウジ)うん！
(アスマ)もう いい…。
Can you trust your source?
もう オレは ここまでだ。
Considering the situation,
it's safe to say we can trust it.
それぐらいは 自分でわかる。
What would you do if it were a trap?
There is a possibility that
Orochimaru is just bait,
…お前たちも わかってるはずだ。
and the Akatsuki will
be waiting there.
うるせぇ！ アンタは だまってろ!!
If it is a trap,
I'll fight with all my might!
いの！
えぇ！
Fight? Kakashi will be in bed
for more than a week.
いの…。
《いの : ここと… ここも…。
But we only have six days left.
For that matter,
急所を ４か所も！》
ever since Sasuke left,
Team Kakashi has been short on staff.
Yes...
We can only add another member
and create a new team.
Lady Tsunade!
What is it?
《これじゃあ… もう！》
Then, you should send a different unit
to investigate the situation.
Even if you let Sakura go,
you should leave out Naruto!
Shizune...
三代目のしたこと➡
Yes.
Like you, Sakura is
one of the few Ninja
今になって
やっとわかった気がする…。
whom I can trust from
the bottom of my heart.
I will definitely let Team Kakashi go,
mostly because Sakura is on it.
オレは… いつも遅すぎる。
Wouldn't it be the same
if my team went?
最後に いの チョウジ シカマル。
It's not the same!
Sakura and Naruto are both
desperately trying
to seek out Sasuke,
their former team mate...
お前たちに
言っておきたいことがある。
They wish to save Sasuke
more than anyone.
先生 もう しゃべっちゃダメだよ！
That strong desire will
lead the mission to success.
(シカマル)チョウジ！ …いのも。
You and Sakura are different...
I understand, but,
for this mission, Naruto should...
アスマ先生の最後の言葉だ。
しっかり聞け。
Now that he's heard this...
what would Naruto say?
いの。
はい。
Let's search for our new team
member immediately!
お前は 気が強いが
面倒見のいい子だ。
Later!
チョウジも シカマルも
コイツらは 不器用だからな。
Sheesh, that impatient brat...
I wasn't done talking yet.
頼む。
はい！
それから サクラには 負けるなよ。
He has a mysterious power...
忍術も 恋もな…。
Everyone...starts wanting
to place their bets on him.
はい！
Becoming Hokage...is my dream...!
チョウジ…➡
The child who was entrusted
with the First Hokage's necklace...
Indeed, Naruto might not
be an ordinary kid.
Sasuke...
お前は 仲間思いの優しい男だ。
Hmm, who might be good?
だからこそ
誰よりも強い忍になる。
I need to think about this
very carefully.
It would be a pain
if I mistakenly choose someone
who would slow me down.
自分に もっと自信をもて。
うん。
Plus, even if the person is skillful,
there might be a problem
with their personality,
それと 少しダイエットしないとな。
and that will ruin the teamwork.
ムリかもしれないけど
がんばってみる。
And Sakura is a sucker
for handsome boys,
so it would be dangerous
if he were too good-looking.
This is hard.
(アスマ)そして シカマル。
Long time no see, Naruto.
お前は 頭がキレるし➡
Huh?
Who are you?
It's me.
Huh?
忍としてのセンスもいい。
Even though we haven't
seen each other for a long time,
you should remember
your comrade's face.
火影にもなれる 器だ。
まあ 面倒くさがり屋のお前は➡
Because the one that spoke
to you will feel bad.
ゲホッ… イヤがるだろうが。
Oh...um...that really indirect speech...
could it be...?
(アスマ)将棋…
お前に 一度も勝てなかったな。
Shino!
You finally remembered.
そういや… 玉の あの話。
If you cover up that much,
no one will know--
((木ノ葉の忍を 駒に例えるなら➡
Shino, you're here early!
シカマル…
さしずめ お前は 桂馬だな。
Are you Kiba?
じゃあ 先生は？
Oh!
オレは なんでもない。 ただの…。
This smell! It is  Naruto!
犠牲駒ってか？
なら 玉は誰か わかるか？
You knew it was me 'cause of that?
That dog, could it be...
(シカマル)火影だろ？
(アスマ)
オレも この間までは そう思ってた。
What are you talking about?
Of course, it's Akamaru!
けど そうじゃなかった。
Huh?!
じゃあ 誰なんすか？
Hey, did you grow?!
(お前も 時がくりゃ わかるさ))
Naw, naw, naw...
Akamaru is the one that grew.
Do dogs become that big
in such a short amount of time?
Really? Since we're always together,
I can't really tell.
あれが誰だか 教えてやる。
耳貸せ。
Can't tell?! That Akamaru,
he used to be on your head!
Right, Shino?!
Seems like you noticed Kiba right away,
didn't you, Naruto?
アスマ… アンタ だから…。
頼んだぞ シカマル…。
Oh shoot, he's upset.
Na...
N-Naruto...
I heard that he came back
to the village.
Wh-What should I do?
(アスマ)けど もう いいよな。
I'm not ready yet since we haven't
seen each other for a while.
やめてた タバコも…。
オレのポーチに入っている➡
What should I say...?
Um... Um...
最後の一服を…。
Oh, it's Hinata!
Why are you hiding?
Huh?! Hinata.
Hey, Hinata, hey, Hinata!
((あっ 悪い 悪い！
Why do you always faint
after seeing Naruto?
今日から
第10班の担当になる 猿飛 アスマだ。
Please! We need a new member!
厳しくするから覚悟しろよ。
いきなり泣くなよ。
Huh?
まだ 厳しくする って
言っただけだろう。
You came at the wrong time,
(煙が 目にしみんだよ！))
we just got a mission and
we're waiting for Kurenai Sensei.
What...I...?
But you have Akamaru,
so lend us one person.
((チョウジ : ライスおかわり！
それから カルビ４人前追加！
Come on, Kiba?
What happened...?
What are you talking about?!
(店員)へい！ お待ち！
うほぉ～！
If I don't go I can't use
the combo attack with Akamaru!
Oh yeah, I met Naruto and...
チョウジ君… キミは 遠慮という
言葉を知っているかね？
Oh that's right.
Then, then...
３千両はいったな。
Hey, Shino is...
You noticed Hinata
right away too, Naruto.
オレは 金が惜しくて
言うわけじゃないんだ。
お前のことを心配して
言うんだぞ。
He is still sulking...
そんなに食べると
このままじゃ デ…。
Forget it!
You guys are all lousy friends!
Naruto's voice...
そいつは禁句だぜ！
Hinata! Just shut up and
come with me!
「デ」ってなに？
どうかしたの？ シカマル？
"Just shut up and come with me"...?
あぁ… で で で デラックスセットも
頼んでいいってよ！
No way... no way... so suddenly...
なっ！
おぉ～！ ホントに？
After all that fuss, I still got rejected.
アスマ先生！ ごっつあんです！
(チョウジ)おにいさん！
デラックスセット２人前！
In that case...
I guess I'll ask those guys.
ライス大盛りでお願い！
(チョウジ)ふぅ～！
Hey, Hinata, Kurenai Sensei
is going to be here soon. Wake up!
(食った！ 食った！))
Hey, Shino! Do you have water?
Water!
The sky...is blue.
((はい。
おう！
I told you already, haven't I?
誰に？
(アスマ)あっ いや 別に誰でも…。
It's annoying, but I'm in charge
of the Chunin Exam.
あっ またな！
I mean, yeah, we have
a long history together,
紅先生によろしくね。
(アスマ)うっ！))
so I want to lend a hand.
《アスマ : な なぜそれを？》
But I'm not in a position
to do whatever I want.
The Fifth appointed me,
so she will kill me if I reject the offer.
I get scolded enough by my mother.
((シカマル : 将棋… 面倒くせぇな。
And here I was thinking
"I can count on Shikamaru,"
(アスマ)いろんな駒の個性を
活かすことで➡
さまざまな局面を
作り出すことができる。
but you go on talking like
it's so annoying and all...
Even if you look at me
with those puppy eyes,
お前のように 作戦を考えるのが
得意なヤツには➡
what's impossible is impossible.
うってつけのゲームだよ。
Then I will lend a hand!
ルールは だいたい
この本を読めばわかる。
Here! Shikamaru.
あとは やりながらだな。
This is the lunch box that
your mom asked me to hand you.
面倒くせぇけど
こんなの10分ありゃ 完璧っすよ。
Choji!
Hey Choji, are you sure you can say
such an irresponsible thing?
まっ 負けた…。
Don't you have a mission
with Asuma and Ino?
(手抜かなくて いいっすよ。 マジで))
I can't ignore what Naruto is saying.
((アスマ : 今回の試験で
中忍になれたのは お前だけだ。
I will try to discuss it
with Asuma Sensei.
担当上忍として オレも鼻が高いぞ。
Choji, thanks!
It's not going to help
(あとは いのとチョウジ。
お前たちも がんばれよ))
if you tell Asuma because
he works under Lady Tsunade.
((アスマ : よく がんばったな。
チョウジ いの。
Well, I will try to talk to him.
Here's the lunch box.
前回 合格したシカマルと合わせて➡
Oh! Thanks!
これで 晴れて
第10班は全員 中忍だ。
Hey, Naruto...
That's my lunch box.
そして ここで… オレも
お前らの担当からは外れる。
これからは
お前ら一人ひとりが隊長になり➡
新たなチームを率いることになる。
(アスマ)このピアスは
オレからの中忍祝いのプレゼントだ。
(オレたちが第10班のチームだったことを
忘れないようにな！))
(いの)先生!!
(いの)うっ… うっ…。
(ライドウ)忍らしい最期だった…。
(シカマル)ゴホッ… ゴホッ…。
やっぱり… タバコは嫌いだ…。
煙が 目に… 染みやがる…。